Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I. Oral History of the American Left Main Series, 1940-2011
  - Alice Dodge Wolfson, Apr 1, 1982; cuid1573
    Interview documents the activities of the League for Industrial Democracy, the Office Workers Union, the New England CIO, and the Socialist Party during the 1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Wolfson 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 279)
    - Transcript (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Workers Party/Standing Fast Conference, May 6, 1983 - May 7, 1983; cuid1574
    Recording of an event commemorating the opening of the Max Shachtman Papers at the Tamiment Library. Panel presentations on 1) the character and activities of the Workers Party, 1940-49 2) Harvey Swados' novel Standing Fast, based on the WP, and 3) three magazines with roots in the WP, Politics, Dissent, and New Politics. Speakers include Herman Benson, Ricky Flanders, Albert Glotzer, Julius Jacobson, Irving Sanes, Morton Clurman, Paul Cowan, Lewis Coser, Robert Cummings, and Phyllis Jacobson.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Workers Party 1-8)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 280A-H)
  - Frederick Wright, Jun 20, 1984; cuid1575
    Wright describes the background of his family and his grandfather's influence on his drawing, his work as a clip-joint musician during the 1920s, going to sea during the 1930s, his work as freelance cartoonist for National Maritime Union (NMU), the Cold War, and his work for the UE News.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Audiocassette Wright 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 281A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Fannie Yellin, Apr 16, 1980; cuid1576
    Yellin describes the anarchist circle in Philadelphia during the 1910s, the personality and ideas of Rudolf Rocker, and the role of the Rocker Circle in Los Angeles in publishing Rocker's work and facilitating his speaking tours.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Yellin 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 282)
  - Karl Yoneda, Jan 7, 1983; cuid1577
    Interview documents the Japanese-American Communist movement in the 1920s-1930s, the Japanese-language press in the 1920s and early 1930s, sectarian errors, cultural events, role in labor movement and opposition to the concentration camps that incarcerated Japanese-Americans during World War II, the Popular Front in the Japanese-American Left, and the state of Asian-American labor in the 1980s.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Yoneda 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 283)
    - Transcript (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Vincent Young, Aug 4, 1983; cuid1578
    Discussion includes Young's youth in New York during the 1920s-1930s, his involvement in a black masonic lodge, and the activities of the Congress of Radical Equality (CORE) in Brooklyn during the 1940s-1960s. Other topics include the Downstate Medical Center, New York World's Fair demonstrations, and housing issues in Brooklyn in the 1980s.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Young 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 284 A-B)
  - Mary Zackheim, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1579
    Interview includes stories about Moshe Nadir and other Jewish literary personalities, Zackheim's philosophies on life, and Zackheim's thoughts on the Communist Party. Second portion of interview is not not Mary Zackheim. It is an unidentified man speaking about Communist Party involvement in a strike.
    Duration: 30 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Mary Zackheim 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 285 A-B)
  - Meyer Zackheim, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1580
    Interview covers the activities of the New York Left in the 1910s-1920s and the problems of the Jewish progressive movement in Miami Beach in the 1970s.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Meyer Zackheim 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 286.5)
  - Meyer Zackheim, Abe Glassman, Florence Glassman, Ben Kliger, and Rosenfeld, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1581
    This group interview, taken in Miami Beach, Florida, collects members' recollections of the progressive Jewish cultural movement in the 1920s-1940s. Topics discussed include how narrators became involved in the movement, trade union activism (especially in the needle trades), strikes, the Workmen's Circle, the Morgen Freiheit, Jewish theatre, music and theatre clubs, and factional divisions on the left.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Zackheim, Glassmans, Klieger & Rosenfeld 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 286)
  - Meyer Zackheim, Archie Rothenberg & Rose Lipshitz, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1582
    Interview regarding the relationship of culture and the Jewish progressive movement. Rose Lipshitz discusses the challenges of immigrant women in America of 1920s and the appeal of the Left. Archie Rothenberg discusses political activities of Jewish Left in 1920s-1930s. Additional topics covered include lectures, union activism in garment and millinery trades, women's roles in trade union and Left political organizations, the Bund and labor activities in Poland, the destruction of Eastern European Jewish communities during the Holocaust, and Yidisher Kultur Farband (YKUF) reading circles.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Zackheim, Rothenberg & Lipshitz 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 287.5)
  - Meyer Zackheim, Ed Weiss, Julius Silver, and Sylvia Silver, Oct 24, 1978; cuid1583
    Group interview concerning the relationship of Jewish culture and left movements in the first decades of the twentieth century. Topics include immigration following the 1905 Russian Revolution, the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU), needle trade strikes, the founding of the Yidisher Kultur Farband (YKUF), political orientations within YKUF, the Morgen Freiheit, the role of women in the YKUF and garment unions, Jewish choruses, the concentration of left activities in Chicago in the early twentieth century, German-American socialist organizations compared with Jewish organizations, the Communist Party's relationship with culture, and the Soviet Union. Group likely also contains Mary Zackheim.
    Duration: 124 minutes over two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Zackheim, Weiss & Silvers 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 287A-B)
  - Joseph Zawadowski, Jul 28, 1983; cuid1584
    Interview documents the activities of the Polish-American Left in Chicago from the time of his father (1920s) to the 1980s and Zawadowski's own experiences in the Spanish Civil War.
    Duration: 124 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Zawadowski 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 288A-B)
  - Steve Zeluck, Dec 15, 1982; cuid1585
    Interview covers the Johnson-Forest Tendency, Trotskyism in Philadephia and Chicago, and Zeluck's reflections on C.L.R. James.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Zeluck 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 289)
  - Steve Zeluck, undated; cuid1586
    Interview includes discussion of the Johnson-Forest Tendency, CLR James, and the Socialist Workers Party.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Zeluck 2)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 410)
  - Charles Zimmerman, Oct 31, 1974; cuid1587
    Interview documents the activities of the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and the struggle between left and right in the 1910s-1920s.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Zimmerman 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 290A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Celia Lewis Zitron - Transcript, May 8, 1976; cuid1588 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Interview documents the activities of the New York Teachers Union during the 1940s.
    Interview by Glenn Goldstein.
- Series II. Fred Zimring Interviews, 1976-1978
  This series contains interviews conducted by Fred R. Zimring as part of the research for his doctoral dissertation, "McCarthyism, the Cold War, and Temple University: the Dismissal of Professor Barrows Dunham from Temple," completed in pursuit of his degree from Teachers College, Columbia University in 1982.
  These transcripts are copies from the Barrows Dunham-Fred Zimring Collection in the Conwellana-Templana Collection at Temple University Libraries.
  - Aptheker, Herbert, July 5, 1977; cuid200
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Apetheker 1)
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 1)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 1)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Axinn, Sidney, January 5, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 2)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 2)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Bodde, Derk, February 25, 1978
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 3)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 3)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Boudin, Leonard, October 16, 1976; cuid201
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Boudin 1)
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 4)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 4)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Bowman, Claude, January 24 and February 21, 1977
    - Access Copy -- January 24 (Box 73, Audiocassette 5A)
    - Original Audio Recording -- January 24 (Box 92, Audiocassette 5A)
    - Access Copy -- February 21 (Box 73, Audiocassette 5B)
    - Original Audio Recording -- February 21 (Box 92, Audiocassette 5B)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Coxe, Spencer, February 25, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 6)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 6)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Diamond, Sigmund, October 24, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 7A, 7B)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 7A-7B)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Dunham, Alice, March 24, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 8)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 8)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Barrows, Dunham, August-September 1976
    - Access Copy, 1976-08-19 (Box 73, Audiocassette 9A)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1976-08-19 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9A)
    - Access Copy, 1976-08-26 (Box 73, Audiocassette 9B)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1976-08-26 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9B)
    - Access Copy, 1976-09-06 (Box 73, Audiocassette 9C)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1976-09-06 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9C)
    - Access Copy, 1976-09-22 (Box 73, Audiocassette 9D)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1976-09-22 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9D)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Dunham, Clarke, May 28, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 10)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 10)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Edelman, Arthur, February 4, 1977; cuid202
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Edelman 1)
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 11)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 11)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Egnal, Abraham, July 25, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 12)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 12)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Forer, Lois, February 15, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 13)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 13)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Fuchs, Ralph, May 19, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 14)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 14)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Gladfelter, Millard, December 1976-February 1977
    - Access Copy, 1976-12-02 (Box 73, Audiocassette 15A, 15B)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1976-12-02 (Box 92, Audiocassette 15A-15B)
    - Access Copy, 1977-02-03 (Box 73, Audiocassette 15C)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1977-02-03 (Box 92, Audiocassette 15C)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Gruber, Jacob, February 7, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 16A, 16B)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 16A-16B)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Haakenson, Robert, March 5, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 17)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Huganir, George, September-October 1976
    - Access Copy, 1976-09-21 (Box 73, Audiocassette 18A)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1976-09-21 (Box 92, Audiocassette 18A)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1976-09-21 (Box 92, Audiocassette 18D)
    - Access Copy, 1976-09-28 (Box 73, Audiocassette 18B)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1976-09-28 (Box 92, Audiocassette 18B)
    - Access Copy, 1976-10-19 (Box 73, Audiocassette 18C)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1976-10-19 (Box 92, Audiocassette 18C)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Johnson, George, September 1977
    - Access Copy, 1977-09-21 (Box 73, Audiocassette 19B)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1977-09-21 (Box 92, Audiocassette 19B)
    - Access Copy, 1977-09-29 (Box 73, Audiocassette 19A)
    - Original Audio Recording, 1977-09-29 (Box 92, Audiocassette 19A)
    - Transcripts (Box 50, Folder 19-20)
  - Knowles, Mary, April 29, 1978
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 21)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 21)
    - Transcript (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Labovitz, Sherman, April 4, 2016
    - Access Copy (Box 73, Audiocassette 22A, 22B)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 22A-22B)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - LeRoy, Gaylord, August 15, 1976; cuid204
    Original cassette tape had sticky shed syndrome. Although the cassette was able to be digitized after baking, there are still transport squeaking noices heard in the files.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd LeRoy 1)
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 23B)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 23B)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - LeRoy, Gaylord, March 12, 1977; cuid203
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd LeRoy 2)
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 23A)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 92, Audiocassette 23A)
  - Levitan, Harry, February 10, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 24)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 24)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Llewellyn, Robert, February 23, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 25)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 25)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Lord, Joseph, July 14, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 26)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Folder 26)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Lustig, Irma, August 25, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 27)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 27)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - MacRae, Wendell S., April 20, 1978
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 28)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 28)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - McClellan, James, December 24, 1976
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 29)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 29)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Meinkoth, Marion, February 17, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 30)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 30)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Merton, Robert, May 18, 1978
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 31)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 31)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Plant, Evelyn, December 8, 1976
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 32)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 32)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Reivich, Isadore, February 14, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 33)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 33)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Roberts, John, April 27, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 34)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 34)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Rome, Edwin, December 29, 1976
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 35)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 35)
  - Rutman, Robert, October 30, 1976
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 36)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 36)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Sawyer, Henry, May 6, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 37)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 37)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Schaeffer, Phil, March 30, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 38)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Short, Raymond, October 21, 1976
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 39)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 39)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Sullivan, Frank, February 21, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 40)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 40)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Tomlinson, William, December 2-3, 1976
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 41A, 41B)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 41A-41B)
  - Wachman, Marvin, April 27, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 42)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 42)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 21)
  - Waldbaum, Saul, October 29, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 43A, 43B)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 43A-43B)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 22)
  - Webster, David, February 22, 1977
    - Access Copy (Box 74, Audiocassette 44)
    - Original Audio Recording (Box 91, Audiocassette 44)
    - Transcript (Box 51, Folder 23)
- Series III. Reynold Hills Project Interviews, 1980-1981; cuid1593
  Interviewees were members of a small colony in upstate New York, which grew from a club called Followers of the Trail. The colony was created by Eastern European Jewish garment workers as a hiking camp for physical exercise and political discussion.
  - A., Murray -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Alexander, Sarah -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - B., Fred -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Breecher, Morris -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Moe -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Brown, Pauline -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - G., Rochelle -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Goldberg, Harry -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - H., Terry -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Knapp, Sepha -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Melman, Florence -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Melman, Jack -- Transcript (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Nechemias, Ann -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Perlman, Dave -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - S., Bertha -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Schoenbach, Harry -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Schoenbach, Rachel -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Schweitzer, Bella -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - T., Anna -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - T., Max -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - U., Feigl -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Ubogy, Wolf -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Yurman, Riva -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Zelin, Anna -- Transcript (Box 53, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Filmmakers' Tapes and Transcripts
  - Seeing Red, 1978-1981; cuid1594
    This subseries contains interviews contributing to a film on American Communism during the 1930s-1950s by Julia Reichert and James Klein of Heartland Productions.
    - Bailey, Bill -- Transcript, July 11, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Frantz, Marge -- Transcript, August 22, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Freidman, David -- Transcript, October 23, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Gray, Ben -- Transcript, undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Gray, Jeannette -- Transcript, undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Hall, Bobbi -- Transcript, undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Healey, Dorothy -- Transcript, August 16, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Hirsch, Carl -- Transcripts, October 13-15, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 8-9)
    - Hunter, Oscar -- Transcript, November 26, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Johnson, Howard -- Transcript, undated (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Krysak, Rose -- Transcript, undated (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Lazarus, Leo -- Transcript, October 28, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Lightfoot, Claude -- Transcript, undated (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Podmaka, Rose -- Transcripts, October 19 and 27, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 15-17)
    - Postek, Stanley -- Transcripts, November 18-19, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
    - Prago, Al -- Transcript, November 17, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Seeger, Pete -- Transcripts, June 10, 1978 and February 19-20, 1982 (Box 57, Folder 4-6)
    - Stoecker, Clarence -- Transcript, October 10, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Women's Group -- Transcript, August 12, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - The Life and Times of Rosie the Riveter, 1976-1979; cuid1595
    These interviews were largely taken between 1976-1977 to contribute to a film about women production workers during World War II by Connie Field of Clarity Productions.
    - Women and World War II -- Research Papers and Published Articles, 1944-1980 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Film Transcript and Synopsis, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Film Press, January 9, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Publicity Materials and Study Questions, circa 1980-1981 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - UAW-CIO Women's Department -- Publications and President's Statement, 1944-1980 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Belcher, Gladys -- Transcripts, undated (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Childs, Lyn -- Transcript, March 31, 1979 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Voltz, Mary, undated
      - Original Audio Recordings (Box 71, Audiocassette 35A, 35B, 35C)
      - Original Audio Recording (Box 72, Audiocassette 35D)
    - Weixel, Lola -- Transcript, August 27, 1977 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Wright, Margaret -- Transcript, November 1977 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - A Crime to Fit the Punishment, 1975-1981
    Interviews from the film A Crime Fit to the Punishment by Barbara Moss and Steve Mack of Moss Productions regarding the making of a film regarding the making of the ealier film Salt of the Earth in 1953-1954.
    - "A Note to Researchers", March 22, 1994 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Biberman, Sonja and Ed Biberman, February 1, 1975
      - Original Audio Recording (Box 72, Audiocassette 43A, 43B)
      - Transcript (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Chacon, Juan, May 21, 1976; cuid205
      - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Chacon 1)
      - Original Audio Recording (Box 72, Audiocassette 46)
      - Transcript (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Chacon, Virginia and Angie Sanchez, May 21, 1976; cuid206
      - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Chacon/Sanchez 1-2)
      - Original Audio Recordings (Box 72, Audiocassette 47A-47B)
      - Transcript (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Jarrico, Sylvia, February 2, 1975
      - Original Audio Recording (Box 72, Audiocassette 48A, 48B)
      - Transcript (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Jencks, Clint, February 15, 1975; cuid208
      - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Jencks 1)
      - Original Audio Recording (Box 72, Audiocassette 49A, 49B, 49C, 49D)
      - Transcript (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Jencks, Clint and Juan Chacon, July 10, 1976; cuid207
      - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Jencks/Chacon 1-2)
      - Original Audio Recordings (Box 72, Audiocassette 50A-50B)
      - Transcript (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Kaplan, Sol, April 9, 1981
      - Transcript (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Scherwin, Jules, 1975-1981
      - Original Audio Recordings, November 11, 1975 (Box 72, Audiocassette 52A, 52B, 52A (copy), 52B (copy))
      - Original Audio Recordings, April 9, 1981 (Box 72, Audiocassette 53A, 53B, 53C)
    - Williams, Henrietta, May 21, 1976
      - Original Audio Recordings, May 21, 1976 (Box 72, Audiocassette 54A, 54B)
      - Transcript (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Tighten Your Belts, Bite the Bullet, 1976-1979; cuid1596
    This subseries contains interviews supporting a film by John Miller of City Crisis Film Group regarding the political and social effects of the mid-1970s urban budget crises in New York and Cleveland.
  - Anarchism in America, 1967-1981; cuid1597